Kevin Mahoney

kjmahoney13@gmail.com • 757.373.7724 • Github: kjmahoney

•kevinmahoney.me

I am a consultant become web developer who is drawn to creative environments. Whether it be brainstorming, planning, coding, debugging, crying, or laughing, I find joy in the process of making things, especially with the goal of producing meaningful change. My skills, experience, and interests lend me many hats to wear in order to be a key player throughout this process.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly—Washington, DC—Development Immersive Student September 2016 - Present

- Built fluency in full-stack web development by completing an intensive three-month program focused on delivering best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development. Examples of projects developed
- Ciku Languages-vocabulary storage and quizzing tool for language learning; built in MEAN stack
- RentMap- Uses Google Maps API to display rent prices and amenities in zip codes across the US; built in Rails and Javascript
- My Harold Team-Note-taking and communication tool for improv teams; built in Ruby on Rails

CGI Federal—Washington, DC—Consultant

September 2014 - September 2016

- Point of contact for the integration of USAID's procurement software (Prism) with its broader financial system (Momentum). Consistently received 10/10 quarterly client satisfaction score
- Led initiative to reorganize financial data to match that of real life mission reorganizations
- Designed and conducted testing activities for enhancements and custom configuration implemented in the system
- Solved ad-hoc process problems for clients on missions around the globe

FabriQate Mobile Technologies—Guangzhou, China—Business Development Intern

May-August 2013

- Developed strategic market entry points for brands entering the mobile app market in China and the Middle East
- Conducted market analysis as well as created pitches and presentations to acquire and maintain clients

Dollar Tree Inc—Chesapeake, VA—Import Logistics Intern

May-August 2012

- Optimized hundreds of shipment load plans from worldwide vendors to be sent to 11 major ports in the US and Canada
- Analyzed freight expense, carrier performance, and procedural evaluations then compiled into comprehensive reports

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

William and Mary Honor Council—Williamsburg, VA—Chief Financial Officer SPRING 2011 - 2013

- Analyzed casework, compiled evidence as well as sat hearing panels to establish a verdict and deliver sanctions
- Elected by a student body consisting of more than 6000 students

Front End Development Javascript, Angular, React, ¡Query, API/AJAX, HTML, CSS, SASS, Three.js, Ruby

Back End Development Rails, Sinatra, Express.js,

Node.js

Databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase

Misc

Mandarin Chinese Git Terminal Excel

EDUCATION

The College of William and Mary

Graduated Cum Laude December 2013 **BBA** in Finance and Chinese Studies

General Assembly

Sept 2016- Present Web Development **Immersive**

Sichuan University 四川大学

Feb-July 2014 Confucius Scholarship

AWARDS/CERTIFICATION

Confucius Institute Scholarship February 2014-\$7500

Clearance

Top Secret exp 2019

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Washington Improv **Theater**-Long Form Improv Performer

DC Language Exchange-Mandarin Language Partner